Guide to the Henry Percy Litchfield Papers 1865-1884 MS 3259
New-York Historical Society
Henry Percy Litchfield papers
1865-1884
New-York Historical Society
Litchfield, Henry Percy, 1847-1919
MS 3259
.83 Linear feet in 2 Hollinger boxes
The Henry Percy Litchfield papers contain translations of German works; drafts of Litchfield's book, The Franco-German War of 1870; unpublished works on the topics of European history, U.S. presidents, religion, and other topics in English, German, French, and Italian; and journals dated 1864-1870 and 1877-1884 covering his extensive European travel, family matters, and social life. In addition, the collection contains a description, dated 1875, of Grace Hill, the family home in Brooklyn, NY.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by item type.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Percy Litchfield (1847-1919) was an amateur historian and translator. He was also the brother of author Grace Denio Litchfield.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Henry Percy Litchfield papers were transferred to The New York Historical from the Special Collections Research Center at George Washington University. Henry Percy Litchfield's sister, Grace Denio Litchfield, gave the papers to George Washington University in 1942.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Percy Litchfield papers contain translations of German works; drafts of Litchfield's book, The Franco-German War of 1870; unpublished works on the topics of European history, U.S. presidents, religion, and other topics in English, German, French, and Italian; and journals dated 1864-1870 and 1877-1884 covering his extensive European travel, family matters, and social life. In addition, the collection contains a description, dated 1875, of Grace Hill, the family home in Brooklyn, NY.
Related Materials
The New York Historical also holds the Litchfield Family Papers (some of Henry Percy Litchfield's papers are included in this large collection.)
Presidents -- United States.; Europe -- Description and travel.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871.; United States -- History.; Diaries.; Literature -- Translations.; Account books.; Letters (correspondence); Litchfield Villa (New York, N.Y.); Litchfield (Family); Litchfield, Grace Denio, 1849-1944
- Journal, 1865-1868 (Offsite-box 1, Item 1)
- Journal, souvenirs of Grace Hill, 1875 (Offsite-box 1, Item 2)
- Journal, 1877-1880 (Offsite-box 1, Item 3)
- Journal, 1880-1884 (Offsite-box 1, Item 4)
- Translated work from German to English: Hacklaender, F.W. Tales for the young, 1875 (Offsite-box 1, Item 5)
- Translated work from German to English: Hacklaender, F.W. Tales for the young, 1876 (Offsite-box 1, Item 6)
- Translated work from German to English: Hacklaender, Otto, Grimm & Bone. Tales from the German, 1876 (Offsite-box 1, Item 7)
- Translated work from German to English: Otto, Emil. Tales for the people, 1876 (Offsite-box 1, Item 8)
- Translated work from German to English: Hacklaender, F.W. Christmas story, 1877 (Offsite-box 1, Item 9)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. The inn in the Spessart, 1879 (Offsite-box 1, Item 10)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. Tales for the young, 1879 (Offsite-box 1, Item 11)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. Hauff's tales, 1879 (Offsite-box 1, Item 12)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. The caravan, 1880 (Offsite-box 1, Item 13)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. The inn in the Spessart, 1880 (Offsite-box 1, Item 14)
- Translated work from German to English: Hauff, William. The sheik of Alexandria and his slaves, 1880 (Offsite-box 2, Item 1)
- Translated work from German to English: Lessing, [Gotthold Ephraima]. Fables (Offsite-box 2, Item 2)
- Original work: Composition, 1868 (Offsite-box 2, Item 3)
- Original work: The Franco-German War of 1870 (2 drafts), 1872 (Offsite-box 2, Item 4a-4b)
- Original work: [History of Europe] (Offsite-box 2, Item 5)
- Original work: [Lives of the Presidents] (Offsite-box 2, Item 6)
- Miscellaneous: [Thoughts on religion], 1861 (Offsite-box 2, Item 7)
- Miscellaneous: [Description of animals (with sketches)], 1865 (Offsite-box 2, Item 8)
- Miscellaneous: German penmanship, 1868 (Offsite-box 2, Item 9)
- Miscellaneous: Travels, 1868-1870 (Offsite-box 2, Item 10)
- Miscellaneous: Conversazione Italiane, 1869 (Offsite-box 2, Item 11)
- Miscellaneous: [Thoughts on religion], 1869 (Offsite-box 2, Item 12)
- Miscellaneous: Account book, 1869-1872 (Offsite-box 2, Item 13)
- Miscellaneous: [Letter from H. Litchfield's mother], 1871 October 8 (Offsite-box 2, Item 14)
- Miscellaneous: Notes of the war between Russia and Turkey, 1877 (Offsite-box 2, Item 15)
- Miscellaneous: Letzioni Italiani (Offsite-box 2, Item 16)
- Miscellaneous: Narration (French history in French) (Offsite-box 2, Item 17)